RG 131, College Club of Hartford
Connecticut State Library
College Club of Hartford records
1905-1944, 1993-2006
Connecticut State Library
College Club of Hartford
1.5 cubic feet
The club was organized at a “mass meeting and rally of college women,” in Hartford on February 11, 1905, with its object “mainly social, philanthropic, or literary.” Among its activities, the Club took a leading role in the establishment of the Spruce Street Settlement, later known as Mitchell House.
RG131
Multiple
Historical Note
The club was organized at a “mass meeting and rally of college women,” in Hartford on February 11, 1905, with its object “mainly social, philanthropic, or literary.” Among its activities, the Club took a leading role in the establishment of the Spruce Street Settlement, later known as Mitchell House.
Scope and Content
The materials consist of meeting minutes, annual reports, financial records, and materials relating to the Club’s activities at Mitchell House and during World War I. Also included are revisions to by-laws published in 1996 and copies of annual programs.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
College Club of Hartford
Subjects:
College Club of Hartford -- Records and correspondence; Clubs -- Connecticut -- Hartford
Document Types:
Correspondence; Programs; Minutes; Reports; Financial records
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
Most of these records were turned over to the Connecticut State Library by vote of the Executive Committee in 1945, others came to the former War Records Department in 1920.
Accruals
Accession 1996-028 has been placed in box 1 of Accession 1945-004. The material is listed as part of Accession 1945-004.
Container List
- Accession 1945-004, 1905-1944, 1993-2006
  - Minutes of general meetings, 1905 February-1931 January; 2 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1905 February - 1916 May, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1916 November - 1931 January, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Executive Board meetings, 1905 June-1940 May; 3 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1905-1913, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1913 May - 1923 October, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1923 October - 1940 May, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Annual meeting reports, 1932-1944, 1993-2006; loose papers + 1 envelope (Box 1)
    Includes minutes of general meetings, committee reports and related materials.
  - Mitchell House material, 1907-1940; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Summary of College Club actions concerning Mitchell House, 1907-1934, and Mitchell House annual report, 1940.
  - World War I material, 1917-1920 (Box 2)
    Reports, correspondence, knitting directions, concert programs, Americanization material, etc.
  - Account book, 1932 May-1939 July; 1 volume (Box 3)
  - Check book, 1922 May-1937 October; 1 volume (Box 3)
    Cancelled checks mounted on stubs.
- Accession 2004-031, 1987-1988, 2003-2004
  - Membership lists, 1987-1988, 2003-2004 (Box shared box)
  - List of speakers, 2003 (Box shared box)
    Handwritten update, 2004; Covers 1970-2004.